Register to The Love Family Papers
Yale University Music Library
The Love Family Papers
1850-1960
MSS 1
Yale University Music Library
3
(11 boxes)
Letters to Lucy Prindle Love and Helen Love Scranton, as well as clippings, photographs, and other items
Love family
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Some of the materials may be stored at the Library's off-campus shelving facility, so researchers should allow at least two business days to have the appropriate boxes paged.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Love Family Papers were established in the Music Library of Yale University by Helen Scranton's cousin, Mrs. William Gaines, in 1969.
Arrangement
In 4 series as follows: I. Correspondence. II. Miscellaneous Correspondence. III. Printed matter. IV. Photographs.
Scope and Contents
The Love Family Papers consist primarily of letters to Lucy Prindle Love and Helen Love Scranton. The correspondence includes letters from composers, conductors, instrumentalists, singers, and critics. The Papers also contain newspaper clippings, photographs, and miscellaneous items.
Biographical / Historical
Lucy Prindle Love and her daughter Helen Love Scranton played an active role in the social and cultural life of New York in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. Helen Scranton was secretary for many years to Franz Kneisel, the founder of the Kneisel String Quartet. After the dissolution of the Quartet in 1917, she served as secretary to both the Society of the Friends of Music and the Beethoven Association of New York.
Composers -- Correspondence; Conductors (Music) -- Correspondence; Music -- United States -- 19th century; Music -- United States -- 20th Century; Singers -- Correspondence; Violinists -- Correspondence; Aldrich, Richard Stoddard, 1902-1986; Altschuler, Modest, 1873-1963; Bagby, Albert Morris, 1859-1941; Barrère, Georges, 1876-1944; Bauer, Harold, 1873-1951; Beach, Amy, 1867-1944; Betti, Adolfo; Bing, Rudolf, 1902-1997; Bingham, Seth, 1882-1972; Bispham, David, 1857-1921; Bloch, Alexander, 1881-1983; Bloch, Ernest, 1880-1959; Bodanzky, Artur, 1877-1939; Bonci, Alessandro, 1870-1940; Bonnet, Joseph, 1884-1944; Bori, Lucrezia, 1887-1960; Bos, Coenraad Valentyn, 1875-1955; Brema, Marie, 1856-1925; Brockway, Howard, 1870-1951; Busoni, Ferruccio, 1866-1924; Cadman, Charles Wakefield, 1881-1946; Carnegie, Andrew, 1835-1919; Carreño, Teresa, 1853-1917; Casals, Pablo, 1876-1973; Chadwick, G. W. (George Whitefield), 1854-1931; Christie, Winifred, 1882-1965; Cortot, Alfred, 1877-1962; Damrosch, Frank, 1859-1937; Damrosch, Walter, 1862-1950; Dannreuther, Gustav, 1853-1923; Déthier, Edouard, 1886-1962; Dippel, Johann Andreas, 1866-1932; Dolmetsch, Arnold, 1858-1940; Eisler, Paul, 1875-1951; Fairchild, Blair, 1877-1933; Farrar, Geraldine, 1882-1967; Farwell, Arthur, 1872-1952; Finck, Henry T., 1854-1926; Fischer, Emil, 1838-1914; Foote, Arthur, 1853-1937; Franko, Sam, 1857-1937; Fremstad, Olive, -1951; Friedberg, Carl, 1872-1955; Fryer, Herbert, 1877-1957; Gabrilowitsch, Ossip, 1878-1936; Gadski, Johanna, 1872-1932; Ganz, Rudolph, 1877-1972; Gauthier, Eva, 1885-1958; Gebhard, Heinrich, 1878-1963; Gerhardt, Elena, 1883-1961; Gilman, Lawrence, 1878-1939; Giorni, Aurelio, 1895-1938; Godowsky, Leopold, 1870-1938; Goldmark, Rubin, 1872-1936; Goodson, Katharine, 1872-1958; Gordon, Jacques; Grau, Maurice, 1849-1907; Graveure, Louis, 1888-1965; Gruenberg, Louis, 1884-1964; Hadley, Henry, 1871-1937; Hale, Philip, 1854-1934; Hall, Marie, 1884-1956; Hamlin, George John, 1868-1923; Harris, Victor, 1869-1943; Hartmann, Arthur, 1881-1956; Henderson, W. J. (William James), 1855-1937; Herman, Reinhold L., 1849-; Hertz, Alfred, 1872-1942; Hess, Ludwig, 1877-1944; Hinton, Arthur, 1869-1941; Hoffman, Richard, 1831-1909; Hofmann, Josef, 1876-1957; Hollaender, Alexis, 1840-1924; Homer, Sidney, 1864-1953; Huhn, Bruno, 1871-1950; Huss, Henry Holden, 1862-1953; Hutcheson, Ernest, 1871-1951; Jacobi, Frederick, 1891-1952; Joseffy, Rafael, 1852-1915; Karl, Tom, 1846-1916; Kelley, Edgar Stillman, 1857-1944; Kindler, Hans, 1892-1949; Klafsky, Katharina, 1855-1896; Kneisel, Franz, 1865-1926; Kobbé, Gustav, 1857-1918; Koemmenich, Louis; Kramer, A. Walter (Arthur Walter), 1890-1969; Krehbiel, Henry Edward, 1854-1923; Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962; Kriens, Christiaan, 1881-1934; Lambert, Alexander, 1862-1929; Leginska, Ethel, 1886-1970; Lehmann, Lilli, 1848-1929; Letz, Hans, 1887-1969; Levitzki, Mischa, 1898-1941; Lhévinne, Josef, 1874-1944; Lilienthal, Abraham Wolf, 1859-1928; Loeffler, Charles Martin, 1861-1935; Lohse, Otto, 1858-1925; Love, Lucy Cleveland Prindle; MacDowell, Edward, 1860-1908; MacDowell, Marian, 1857-1956; Mannes, David, 1866-1959; Martin, Riccardo, 1874-1952; Mason, Daniel Gregory, 1873-1953; Mason, William, 1829-1908; Meader, George, 1888-1963; Meltzer, Charles Henry, 1853-1936; Mitropoulos, Dimitri, 1896-1960; Moiseiwitsch, Benno, 1890-1963; Nevin, Arthur, 1871-1943; Nordica, Lillian, 1857-1914; Olitzka, Rosa, 1873-1949; Parker, H. T. (Henry Taylor), 1867-1934; Parker, Horatio W. (Horatio William), 1863-1919; Patti, Adelina, 1843-1919; Piastro, Mishel, 1891-1970; Plançon, Pol, 1851-1914; Powell, Maud, 1867-1920; Rains, Leon, 1870-1954; Randolph, Harold, 1861-1927; Reimers, Paul; Rogers, Francis, 1870-1951; Rothwell, Walter H. (Walter Henry), 1872-1927; Rubinstein, Artur, 1887-1982; Safonov, Vasiliĭ Ilʹich, 1852-1918; Salzedo, Carlos, 1885-1961; Samaroff Stokowski, Olga, 1882-1948; Saminsky, Lazare, 1882-1959; Sandby, Herman, 1881-1965; Schelling, Ernest, 1876-1939; Schindler, Kurt, 1882-1935; Schulz, Leo, 1865-1944; Schumann-Heink, Ernestine, 1861-1936; Scranton, Helen D. Love (Helen Douglas Love), 1879-1968; Sembrich, Marcella, 1858-1935; Shelley, Harry Rowe, 1858-1947; Smith, David Stanley, 1877-1949; Smith, Gerrit, 1859-1912; Spalding, Albert, 1888-1953; Spiering, Theodore, 1871-1925; Steinway, William, 1836-1896; Sternberg, Constantin Ivanovich, Edler von, 1852-1929; Stock, Frederick, 1872-1942; Stojowski, Sigismund, 1870-1946; Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977; Stransky, Josef, 1872-1936; Svečenski, Louis, 1862-1926; Tapper, Thomas, 1864-1958; Ternina, Milka, 1863-1941; Thomas, Theodore, 1835-1905; Thursby, Emma Cecilia, 1845-1931; Toscanini, Arturo, 1867-1957; Hoose, Ellison van, 1868-1936; Vogrich, Max, 1852-1916; Warren, George William, 1828-1902; Warren, Samuel P. (Samuel Prowse), 1841-1915; Whithorne, Emerson, 1884-1958; Whiting, Arthur, 1861-1936; Willeke, Willem; Wood, Mary Knight, 1857-1944; Zadora, Michael, 1882-1946; Love family; Kneisel Quartet
- Correspondence, Series I
  - Aldrich, Richard, 1918 Jan 29; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Altschuler, Modest(e), 1906; postcard (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alvary, Thekla (wife of Max Alvary), 1898; 6 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alvary, Thekla (wife of Max Alvary), 1899-1902; 6 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bachaus (Backhaus), Wilhelm, 1922; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bagby, Albert Morris, 1897-1902; 9 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bagby, Albert Morris to (Walter?) Pamresch, 1894 Apr 18; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Barrère, George, 1904-1920; 17 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bauer, Harold, 1903-1923; 12 autograph letters signed, postcard (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bauer, Harold, 1924-1927; 12 autograph letters signed (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bauer, Harold to Mannes, no year Apr 23; autograph letter signed (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Beach, Amy M., 1916-1917; 4 autograph letters signed (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Beach, Amy M. to Franz Kneisel, 1916 Oct 11; autograph letter signed (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Beach, Amy M., 1916 Nov 29; card (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bingham, Seth to Franz Kneisel, 1912-1913; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bispham, David, 1893-1898; 5 autograph letters signed (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bispham, David, 1898-1899; 4 typed letters signed (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bispham, David, 1899; 18 autograph letters signed (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bispham, David, 1900-1901; 10 autograph letters signed (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bispham, David, 1902; 17 autograph letters signed (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bispham, David, 1903-1904; 18 autograph letters signed (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bispham, David, 1903 Jul 31; card (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bispham, David, 1904; 13 autograph letters signed (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bispham, David, card (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bispham, David, 1908-1909; 19 autograph letters signed, 6 postcards (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bispham, David, 1910-1912; 10 autograph letters signed (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bispham, David, 1912; 4 typed letters signed (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bispham, David, 1914-1920; 8 autograph letters signed (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bispham, David, 1915 Mar 25; autograph letter signed (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bispham, David, 1915-1920; 13 typed letters signed (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bispham, David, no date; 24 autograph letters signed, autograph programs (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Black, Sara W. (Cahier, Mme. Charles), no date; autograph letter signed (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bloch, Alexander to Franz Kneisel, 1914; autograph letter signed (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bloch, Ernest, 1918-1920; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Bloch, Ernest, 1921 Nov 3; typed letter signed (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Bodanzky, Arthur, 1919-1922; 4 autograph letters signed, postcard, program (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Boeckelman, Bernardus, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bonci, Allessandro, no date; card (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bonnet, Joseph, 1920 Sep 24; autograph letter signed (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bori, Lucrezia, 1933; 3 typed letters signed, 2 autographs (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bos, Coenrad, van, 1921; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Brema, Marie, 1895-1903; 5 autograph letters signed (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Brockway, Howard, 1902-1923; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Buonamici, Carlo, 1911-1913; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Busoni, Ferruccio, 1915; autograph letter signed (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Cadman, Charles Wakefield to Franz Kneisel, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cadman, Charles Wakefield, 1911; postcard (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Carnegie, Andrew, 1898; typed letter signed (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Carreño, Teresa, 1899-1902; 12 autograph letters signed, 2 cards (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Carreño, Teresa, 1903-1916; 9 autograph letters signed, 2 autographs (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Casals, Pablo, 1920 Apr 10; autograph letter signed (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Casals, Susan Metcalfe, no date; 3 autograph letters signed, card (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Chadwick, Georg Whitefield, 1903-1916; 3 typed letters signed (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cheathan, Thompson, Catherine, 1903-1904; 4 autograph letters signed (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Consolo, Ernesto, 1908-1914; 7 autograph letters signed, signed bills (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cortot, Alfred, 1929 Dec 29; autograph letter signed, autograph program (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Damrosch, Frank to Helen Love, 1895-1921; 8 autograph letters signed (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Damrosch, Frank to Lucy Love, 2 autograph letters signed, 12 typed letters signed, poscard (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Damrosch, Walter to Lucy Love, 1893-1896; 10 autograph letters signed, 5 typed letters signed, postcard (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Damrosch, Walter to Lucy Love, 1893-1896; 12 autograph letters signed, 11 typed letters signed (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Damrosch, Mrs. Margaret B., 1894-1929; 5 autograph letters signed (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Dannreuther, Gustav, 1898-1902; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Déthier, Edouard, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dippel, Andreas, 1902 Nov 22; autograph letter signed (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dippel, Andreas, 1909-1910; 2 typed letters signed (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dolmetsch, Arnold, 1901-1905; 4 autograph letters signed (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Eisler, Paul, 1920 Mar 13; autograph letter signed (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Fairchild, Blair, 1912 May 24; autograph letter signed (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Farrar, Geraldine, 1898-1899; 11 autograph letters signed (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Farrar, Henriette, no date; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Farwell, Arthur, 1917 Mar 30; autograph letter signed (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Farwell, Arthur, 1917 May 22; typed letter signed (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Finck, Henry Theophilus, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Fischer, Emil, 1899-1901; 8 autograph letters signed (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Fischer, Emil, 1899 Dec 18; card (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Foote, Arthur to Miss Seaver, no date; 8 autograph letters signed (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Franko, Sam, 1898-1935; 5 autograph letters signed, 3 cards (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Friedberg, Carl, 1917; autograph letter signed, postcard (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Fryer, Herbert (George), 1916; autograph letter signed (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Gabrilowitsch, Ossip to Helen Love, 1914-1918; autograph letter signed, 14 typed letters signed (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Gabrilowitsch, Clara Clemens, 1920; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Gabrilowitsch, Clara Clemens, 1918; 7 typed letters signed (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Gadski, Johanna Tauscher, 1895-1898; 5 autograph letters signed (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Gadski, Johanna Tauscher, 1903 Mar 20; typed letter signed, 3 autographs (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Gale, Clement Rowland, 1891 Oct 4; autograph letter signed (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Ganz, Rudolf, 1911-1921; 6 autograph letters signed (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Ganz, Rudolf, 1916 Mar 16; typed letter signed (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Ganz, Rudolf, 1913-1915; 2 cards (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Gauthier, Eva, 1920-1922; 5 autograph letters signed (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Gebhart, Heinrich, 1907-1913; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Genovese, Nana, 1921 Nov 21; card (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Gerhart, Elena, 1921-1922; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Gilman, Lawrence, 1914-1918; 4 typed letters signed (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Giorni, Aurelio, 1914-1917; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Godowsky, Leopold, 1917 Jan 3; typed letter signed (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Godowsky, 1916 Oct 17 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    General
    See Newmann, Wight F.
  - Goldmark, Rubin, 1918-1921; 21 autograph letters signed (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Goldmark, Rubin, 1920; 1 card (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Goodson, Katharine, 1909-1915; 4 autograph letters signed (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Goodson, Katharine, 1914-1915; 2 typed letters signed (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Goodson, Katharine, 1914 Mar 7; card (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Gordon, Jacques, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Graveure, Louis, 1921 Oct 25; typed letter signed (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Grau, Maurice, 1898; 2 typed letters signed (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Gruenberg, Louis, 1922 Feb 2; autograph letter signed (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Habelmann, Theodore, 1902-1903; 4 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Habelmann, Theodore, 1903-1904; 4 cards (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hadley, Henry (Kimball) to Franz Kneisel, 1915-1916; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hadley, Henry (Kimball) to Lucy Love, 1904-1919; 5 autograph letters signed, card (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hale, Philip, 1916; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hall, Marie (Mary Paulina), 1902-1938; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hamlin, George, 1903-1922; 6 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hamlin, George, no date; 3 typed letters signed (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Harris, Victor, 1898-1933; 7 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Harris, Victor, 1914; typed letter signed (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Hartmann, Arthur, 1921; typed letter signed (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Heffley, Eugene, 1905; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Henderson, William James, 1916; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Henschel, Helen, 1902; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Herman, Reinhold Ludwig, 1894-1914; 30 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Hertz, Alfred, 1908; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hertz, Alfred, 1921; card (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hess, Ludwig, 1912; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Heyman, Sir Henry, 1921; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hinton, Arthur to Mrs. Seaver, 1909-1912; 8 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hinton, Arthur to Franz Kneisel, 1913; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hinton, Arthur to Helen Love, 1913-1914; 6 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hoffmann, Richard, 1890; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Hofmann, Josef, 1919; typed letter signed (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Hollaender, Alexis, 1902-1903; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Hollaender, Alexis, 1902; postcard (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Homer, Sidney, 1908-1912; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Homer, Sidney, 1902; typed letter signed (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Huhn, Bruno, 1899; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Huss, Henry Holden, 1894-98; 18 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Huss, Henry Holden, 1898; 15 autograph letters signed, postcard, callcard (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Huss, Henry Holden, 1899; 21 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Huss, Henry Holden, 1900-1902; 15 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Huss, Henry Holden, 1902; 14 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Huss, Henry Holden, 1903-1905; 15 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Huss, Henry Holden, 1906-1909; 16 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Huss, Henry Holden, 1909-1917; 11 autograph letters signed, 6 callcards, 14 musical greetings (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Hutcheson, Ernest, 1921; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Jacobi, Frederick, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Joseffy, Rafael, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Karl, Tom, 1898; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Kelley, Edgar Stillman, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Kindler, Hans, 1919; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Kindler, Hans, 1921; 2 cards (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Kneisel, Franz, 1913-1916; 14 typed letters signed, 8 autographs, 3 programs (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Kobbe, Gustav, 1898; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Koemmenich, Louis, no date; card (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Kramer, Arthur Walter, 1917; 4 autograph letters signed, card (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Krehbiel, Henry Edward, 1898; 6 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Kreisler, Fritz, 1917 Jun; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Kreisler, Fritz, 1917-1960; 3 typed letters signed (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Kriens, Christiaan to Franz Kneisel, no date; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Kriens, Christiaan to Helen Love, 1908; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Lambert, Alexander, no date; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Leginska, Ethel, no date; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Lehmann, Lilli, 1906-1928; 12 postcards, 6 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Leroy, Henri Leon, 1913; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Letz, Hans, no date; 28 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Letz, Hans, 1913-1918; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Levitzki, Mischa, 1921; postcard (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Lhévinne, Joseph, 1908-1920; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Lhévinne, Joseph, 1906-1934; 2 cards (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Lhévinne, R., 1907; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Lilienthal, Abraham W., 1919; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Loeffler, Charles Martin, 1916-1919; 4 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Lohse, Otto, 1896-1897; 5 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Longy, Gustave Georges Leopold, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Love, Helen to Ossip Gabrilowitsch, 1917 Feb 16; typed letter signed (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - MacDowell, Edward, 1898 Dec 2; typed letter (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - MacDowell, Edward, 1898 Mar 8; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - MacDowell, Marian, 1902 Oct 17; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - MacDowell, Fannie, 1901 Oct 23; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Mannes, David Daniel, 1899-1912; 6 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Mannes, David Daniel, 1915 May 10; typed letter signed (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Martin, Ricardo (Hugh Whitfield), 1907 Dec 8; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Mason, Daniel Gregory, 1914-1915; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Mason, William, no date; musical greeting card (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Mattfeld, Marie, 1922; typed letter signed (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Meltzer, Charles Henry to Mrs. Seaver, 1911-1912; 6 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Meltzer, Charles Henry to Franz Kneisel, 1911 Oct 27; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Meyn, Heinrich to Lucy Love, 1899-1817; 4 autograph letters signed (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Meyn, Heinrich to Franz Kneisel, 1911 Feb 9; autograph letter signed (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Mitropoulos, Dimitri, 1956-1957; 2 typed letters signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Moisewitsch, Benno, 1919 Dec 5; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Morgen, Agnes, 1912 Dec 2; autograph letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Mukle, May Henriette, 1917 Nov 11; autograph letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Neumann, Wight F., 1916 Oct 17; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
    See Godowsky
  - Nevin, Arthur Finley to Franz Kneisel, 1913 Nov; autograph letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Nevin, Arthur Finley to Helen Love, 1915; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Nordica, Lillian, no date; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Palmer, Courtland A. to Mr. Seaver, 1908; 7 autograph letters signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Palmer, Courtland A. to Helen Love, 1921; autograph letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Parker, Henry Taylor to Mrs. Seaver, 1905-1908; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Parker, Henry Taylor to Helen Love, 1917 Nov; card (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Parker, Horatio William to Lucy Love, 1902 Oct; autograph letter signed (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Parker, Horatio William to Franz Kneisel, 1917; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Patti, Adelina, 1902; autograph letter signed (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Phelps, Wm Lyon, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Piastro, Mishel, 1922 Apr 11; autograph letter signed (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Plançon, Pol, 1898 Feb 4; autograph letter signed (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Pollain, Rene, 1921 Feb 10; autograph letter signed (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Powell, Maud to Franz Kneisel, 1912 Mar 2; autograph letter signed (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Powers, Francis Fischer, 1899 Feb 6; autograph letter signed (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Rains, Leon, 1898 Nov 14; autograph letter signed (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Randolph, Harold to Seaver, 1907-1912; 18 autograph letters signed (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Randolph, Harold to Mrs. Seaver, 1909-1910; 2 cards (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Randolph, Harold to Helen Love, 1903-1913; 14 autograph letters signed (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Randolph, Harold to Helen Love, 1913-1919; 7 typed letters signed (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Randolph, Harold to Franz Kneisel, 1912 Feb; autograph letter signed (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Reimers, Paul, no date; autograph letter signed, typed letters signed (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Resky, Gustavo Bernal, 1905; 2 cards (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Roentgen, Julius to Mrs. Seaver, 1910; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Roentgen, Julius, 1912; 8 signed bills (Box 6, Folder 4)